(futuristic instrumental music)
- [Instructor] We've created
a game manager object
that has our game manager script,
that now can control all
the different prefabs
that we have.
Now what we'll need to do
is we want to instantiate them over time,
so I'll use a coroutine again,
and we'll learn about a
new loop that we can use
to do that.
In our game manager script,
we're actually going to
create a new method first.
Now, we're going to create
another Ienumerator method,
called SpawnTarget.
That way, we can actually use
the wait for seconds method
to control the length of
time between each spawn.
We need to use the yield keyword again.
And we need to return
a new WaitForSeconds,
and it needs a float of seconds.
For now, we'll just use spawnRate
because we'll create the variable later.
Now we need to actually
get a random object
from our list to use,
so we'll use our index,
so we can select that object in the list
using its position.
We'll get a random number
between the first object
and the last object,
so similar to how in
arrays we got the length.
We can use targets, but in this case,
we actually got the count,
and so this will actually
give us the count
of how many objects are in that list.
In this case, it's four,
so it'll be a random number
between zero and four,
and then we need to actually
instantiate that object.
So using our targets, we select the one
at the index that we're gonna use,
so that way we either get our bad object
or one of our three good objects.
Now, the loop that we're
gonna use to control this
is called a while loop.
And a while loop is a fusion
between a for loop and an if statement.
So an if statement requires a condition
to tell it when to stop.
A for loop will iterate over
something a certain number
of times to execute your code.
So while loop will execute
your code continuously,
but instead of giving it a
defined number of times to run,
we can actually use a condition
to tell it when it should
actually stop running.
We don't actually have a condition
we're gonna use just yet.
So we'll just set this to be true.
So while this is true,
which will always be,
we can do our line of code
here to spawn our object.
Our spawnRate is still mad at us,
because it hasn't been initialized yet,
so we'll create a
private float, spawnRate,
and we'll set that to one for now,
so it'll spawn every one second.
Now, in our start method,
we'll use a coroutine
to actually start that spawn timer,
so if we StartCoroutine, SpawnTarget,
now, after we've saved,
if we go to play our game,
you should see through the
magic of our programming
that we have all of these
different obstacles,
even though they're
running into each other,
that's totally fine.
You can see it's randomly
creating different obstacles
over time.
What you're gonna do in
your game manager class,
make sure you create a spawnRate
to keep track of the number of seconds
that you want something to spawn.
You're going to create
another IEnumerator method
for our SpawnTarget, we're
going to use a while loop,
and for now our condition will just be
that it's always true.
In our while loop, we will yield return,
the WaitForSeconds using the spawnRate
that we actually want to spawn at,
so one every second.
You're going to get the index
of an object to choose from our list,
and then you're actually
going to instantiate
that object using the index to grab it
from our targets list.
And then in our start method,
just create a coroutine
using StartCoroutine,
and then call our SpawnTarget method.
Now it's your turn.
(futuristic instrumental music)