(synthetic vibrations)
- [Narrator] Now let's make
our fifth prototype project.
We're going to open up
Unity Hub once again.
Once the application is opened,
we're going to create a new project.
We're still making a 3D project.
This will be Prototype 5.
Make sure you save it
in the right location,
in that folder we were using
for all of our other projects.
Select Create.
Now Unity has set up
our new empty project.
So, if you head back over to
the webpage for the tutorial,
download the asset package,
either through the asset store
or through the direct download.
Import all of the different
assets for Prototype 5.
Close the asset store tab.
In your Assets folder
in the project window,
select your Scenes folder,
open up Prototype 5,
delete your SampleScene.
Now let's reposition to our camera.
So now you can see our
background for Prototype 5.
In fact, our camera is
currently set to this 2D view,
so we can actually just
set our scene view to 2D.
This will, in fact, actually
make it easier for us
to interact with this scene.
Because while we do have
3D objects we're using,
we're generally just going to be working
on this 2D plane, here.
We could have done that for
some of our other projects,
but it's always good to get comfortable
moving things around in the 3D space.
In fact, if we select our move tool now
and select our Background, for example.
We actually only have arrows
for the y and the x-axis.
There's no z-axis because we
can't go forwards or backwards.
We can only go up, down, left or right.
And then, one more thing that we can do,
if you want to, go to your Course Library
in your Assets folder.
In the Textures folder, expand that
and there's actually all
these different textures
that we can use.
So, for example, I could replace
these dark panels on the side.
Then I could make my center panel
have a dark background.
For now, I'm just going
to leave it as it was.
So I'm going to undo all that.
And now we're ready to get started.
So, what you're gonna
do is open up Unity Hub,
create a new project,
make it 3D, rename it to Prototype 5
and make sure it's saved
in the right location.
Once Unity sets up your empty project,
head over to the tutorial webpage,
download the starter package,
either through the asset
store or direct download,
import your asset package.
Once the package is imported,
open up your Scenes folder,
open Prototype 5, delete your SampleScene.
Set your scene view to 2D
with the little 2D button
in the top left of our scene view.
And then, if you want, you
can go into the Assets folder
underneath Course Library,
open up that textures folder
and you can apply different
textures to the background
just by left clicking and dragging them
onto either of the panels
or that main middle section
if you want to change the colors around.
Now it's your turn.
(synthetic vibrations)