(futuristic noises)
- [Narrator] So we have our
script for our target set up.
We're just gonna do a
little bit of clean-up
just because we have a lot
of these different methods,
and we have a lot of
different hard values,
so we're going to make our
code just a bit more readable.
So we have values for our Speed,
we have values for our Torque
that we're gonna apply.
We have a Range for x position,
and we have our Spawn position,
so we'll just create a
bunch of those variables.
So we'll make a private
float for our minSpeed,
our minimum speed.
And we'll set this to 12 for now.
We'll make another float for our max
and this will be 16.
For our Torque, we'll
make a torque variable
and we'll set this to be 10.
And then we have a Range
that our x can spawn in
and we have a position for our y.
Now, we'll go in and replace
all these values really quick
so in our Random.Range for our AddForce,
we're going to change our
12 to be the minimum speed
that we want our objects to move.
And then we'll change the
16 to the maximum speed
across our Random.Range.
For our Torque, we'll apply our max torque
for the negative values
and the positive values.
So this way, it's just using maxTorque
to see the Range that it should
be creating random numbers at.
And then finally, for our position,
we'll change the Range
that our object spawns at
to our xRange between
negative four and four
and then we can just
remove the negative six
so we'll make this the actual ySpawnPos.
Now, if we wanted to make our code
a little bit more readable,
we could create random variables
for the x Random Torque,
y Random Torque, and z Random Torque.
That doesn't really save us
any lines of code really,
so it's not entirely useful to do.
But what we can do is since we have
all of these different lines
that are each doing one specific task,
we can put these into methods
to make it a bit easier
for when we need to use them.
So, we'll make a new Vector3 method
so that way we can return to Vector3.
And this will be for our RandomForce,
so here' where we'll
calculate a RandomForce
and then send it back to us.
And then in fact, we
can just have it return
this entire line of code in our AddForce.
So we'll cut that with Ctrl or Command X,
paste it down in RandomForce
with Ctrl or Command V,
and now in our AddForce method,
we can actually just call
our RandomForce method.
We can do the same thing for the Torque,
since Random just returns a float,
we'll use our float,
call this RandomTorque
so it generates a different
Torque value every time.
Could actually just take our Random.Range,
have it return that Random.Range
and then we can just call RandomTorque.
And then, if we just cut
out all the random ranges,
then we'll just paste
our RandomTorque method
into each of those different parameters.
And then, last but not least,
since we're creating a
random spawn position,
we can just use a method to do that too.
So, again, we'll create another Vector3,
since we're using a Vector3.
We could take where we create
our actual random spawn position,
if we cut that out of our start method.
In our Vector3 we return and then we paste
that entire line of code.
Now, one thing you might notice
between our RandomSpawnPos method,
that returns Vector3, and
RandomForce that returns Vector3,
is that our RandomForce does
not use the new keyword,
versus our RandomSpawnPos, which does.
That's because, with RandomForce,
because we're multiplying a
Vector3 that already exists,
and multiplying it by values,
we can return that Vector3 immediately.
In our RandomSpawnPos,
because we're actually
creating a new Vector3,
we actually need to use the new keyword
to create a new Vector3 variable
with values that we can then use.
And then in our transform.position,
we can just call RandomSpawnPos.
So, now our code is a lot more clean
in the places where we're really
using our different methods.
It's much easier to
read, we have variables
so we can change them whenever we need to.
And then, in our different helper methods,
we're doing different things
like calculating a RandomForce
so that we can use it, or a RandomTorque,
or a RandomPos.
Now it's your turn.