(futuristic music)
- In this prototype, objects
will be tossed into the air,
and the user has to click
on them to destroy them.
So, the first thing you'll do is decide
what kind of objects
you want to obliterate.
You could choose between sports balls.
You could choose fruits and veggies.
You could even choose the ingredients
from my favorite healthy breakfast,
pizza, cookies, and energy drinks.
Whatever you choose,
by the end of this lesson
the objects you want
will be launched into the air,
and when you click on
them, they'll be destroyed.
To make this game as fun
and fast-paced as possible,
we're going to give these
objects not one, not two,
but three randomized variables.
The position along the
bottom of the screen
will be randomized so the
objects can appear from anywhere.
The upward force will be randomized
so that the objects fly
up to random heights.
And the spin or torque we apply
will also be randomized so that
some objects spin this way,
some spin that way,
and some barely spin at all.
As you can imagine,
our old friend Random.Range is
going to be heavily involved
in all of this.
To destroy the objects,
we'll also be testing for a
brand new type of user input,
the mouse.
Unity can easily detect
where and when a mouse has
been clicked in your game.
You can tell when the
mouse enters an area.
You can tell when the mouse
button has been pressed down.
You can even tell when the
mouse button has been released.
All you have to do is
detect if a user has clicked
one of our objects,
and if they have, we'll destroy it.
So, to make all that happen,
I'll see you in Unity.
(futuristic music)