(computerized chirping)
- [Narrator] Now that we have
a mostly functional vehicle,
there is one other big
bug we should try to fix.
The car can still
accelerate and decelerate,
turn and increase in
speed and RPM in mid-air.
So how do we make it so
the vehicle only moves
when it's on the ground?
Once again, we'll head
over to the internet
to see if there's any solutions.
So I looked up how to test
if wheels are on the ground in Unity.
And there's a couple of options
here, there's Unity Answers,
which is from a few years ago, could work.
There's one from 2005, there's
the official documentation.
We'll take a look at the
documentation for now.
So it says that there's just
WheelCollider.isGrounded,
it's a Boolean that says if it's grounded.
Indicates whether the
wheel currently collides
with something.
That seems like it's good
enough to get the job done.
So first what we need to
do is we actually need
to get all of our wheels as references,
so we can actually track them.
So, I'm going to create a
new list of wheel colliders
in my PlayerController script.
So I need to actually
assign these variables,
so I'll serialize this.
We'll call it a list.
We need to make it a type of WheelCollider
and we can name it allWheels,
so we can keep track of all of our wheels.
So now that we've added that list
to our PlayerController script,
we do actually need to
set the size of this list.
In this case we have four wheels,
so we need to set the size to four
and now, we drag in each of our wheels
as different elements.
So, that's the front left wheel,
this is the front right wheel,
this is the rear left, and
this is the rear right.
So now that we've assigned
references to all of our wheels,
we'll need to create a new variable
just to see how many
wheels are on the ground.
We need to keep track
of the number of wheels,
so we actually need an integer,
so we'll say int and then
we'll call it wheelsOnGround,
so that we can keep track of the number
of wheels that are on the ground.
After our Update method,
we'll create a new method,
in fact, to keep track
of the number of wheels,
so, call it void and we'll just call it
the count of our wheels.
So we need to keep track of
the count of our wheels on the ground,
so we use wheelsOnGround,
we set this to zero
because we'll assume that there
are no wheels on the ground.
Now, a cool thing that
we can do with lists
is something similar to the way
that we used for-loops to
iterate through something before.
So with for-loops you
could set the end condition
of when the for-loop would stop.
With lists we can actually
use the for-each loop.
So we type foreach,
and then we actually use parentheses.
Now in our for-each we need to tell it
what we're trying to find in our list.
So, we're trying to find WheelColliders,
we need to give a name
to that WheelCollider,
so we'll just call each
wheel that we go through.
And now we need to give it the list
that it's actually gonna go
through, so in allWheels.
Then after this we put curly braces,
so now, we're in our for-each loop.
So what we're gonna do is, if each wheel,
and now we can use the
isGrounded attribute.
So, if our wheel is grounded,
wheelsOnGround, plus, plus.
So, just to think about
how this will work,
when we call the count
wheels method it will
go through each wheel
in our list of wheels,
so the front left, front right,
rear left, and rear right wheel.
So, maybe it goes through the front left,
that wheel is not grounded,
it will not add a number
to the wheelsOnGround.
Front right that is
grounded, so it will add one
to wheelsOnGround.
Rear right also grounded,
so it'll add another one.
Rear left not grounded,
so it will not add one.
So then we're left with
two wheelsOnGround,
the right side wheels, but
not the left side wheels.
Now this could be useful, however,
what we're actually looking
for is to know when our wheels
are on the ground.
We don't just want to keep track
of the wheels on the ground,
we actually want to know when our vehicle
is entirely on the ground.
So I'm actually going to change
this method a little bit.
So, void doesn't actually
give us any value back,
so we actually need to return a value
and we'll actually return a bool.
And instead of CountWheels,
we can just say IsOnGround.
So now if I call the IsOnGround method,
it should give us back a true or false.
True if all four wheels are on the ground,
false if none of the
wheels are the ground,
if less than four wheels
are on the ground.
So now we're keeping
track of how many wheels
are on the ground.
So we can actually just
use another if statement.
So if the wheelsOnGround
is equal to four,
if all of the wheels are on the ground,
we return true and keep doing
whatever we want it to do,
else, we return false.
So if less than four
wheels are on the ground,
then we don't want our vehicle to move.
So now that we are keeping track of
whether our vehicle's
on the ground or not.
In our Update method, we
should actually prevent
the player from being able
to move when they're not
on the ground.
So, in fact I can actually
just wrap this entire statement
here in an if statement,
so if IsOnGround,
parentheses here,
delete this, put all
of this in parentheses,
in brackets I should say.
So, if IsOnGround, returns true,
because all of our
wheels are on the ground,
then it will update our forces,
rotate our vehicle and give us the RPM.
Otherwise, it will return
false and we won't be able
to move our vehicle.
So if I save this, pop back
into Unity and press play,
now I can move the vehicle.
And then you can see that
my speed and my RPM stop,
because I left the ground.
So, what you're gonna do is in
your PlayerController script,
you're going to create a
list of wheel colliders
called allWheels.
In Unity, in your Player Object,
under the PlayerController script,
an allWheels variable should appear,
make sure to set the size to four
and then make sure to
drag each different wheel
into each element.
So the front left, front right,
rear left, and rear right.
Once you've done that, create
another variable to keep track
of how many wheels are on
the ground as an integer.
You're then going to create a new method
that returns a boolean
value called IsOnGround,
where you'll set the wheels on the ground
to zero, initially.
You will then loop through
the allWheels list,
by using a for-each loop and
you need to use the syntax
for each wheel collider
wheel in the allWheels list.
Inside of that for-each
loop, just do a check
to make sure that the wheel is grounded
and if it is, to increase
wheelsOnGround by one.
So that way, if the
wheels are on the ground,
all four of them, you return true,
otherwise you return false.
And then in your Update
method you're going
to wrap your place in your
code where you apply forces,
rotate the vehicle, and set
the RPM into an if statement
that checks if the
vehicle is on the ground,
then you can do all these things.
So then you can pop into
Unity and test your game
and see if your script worked.
Now it's your turn.