- [Instructor] Now that we've
implemented real physics
on the vehicles, it's
very easy to overturn.
We need to figure out a way
to make our vehicles safer to drive.
So if I test out my game again,
as I drive my vehicle down
the road, at some point,
it just kind of flips over
and that definitely isn't
great, oh it flipped back.
That's cool.
Oh, there you go, oh, full rotation, cool.
My back on the ground, so.
While this looks kind of cool,
this is not what we're
trying to accomplish at all.
But how do we fix this problem?
We'll head back to the internet
and see if anybody has
any solutions for us.
So, I actually Googled unity
prevent car from flipping.
There's a couple of things that pop up.
There's some YouTube videos.
There's Unity Answers posts.
I'm just gonna check out
this first link here.
This actually brings me to
the forums on our website.
So, How to prevent the
Car from tilting/flipping.
"I have some problems
with the car I'm creating.
"I have a simple car
that has a rigid body,
"four wheels, wheel colliders."
What is that?
"Using a script."
Let's see what are the responses.
"Lower the center of gravity
of the car's rigid body."
What does that mean?
Okay.
Let's see if there's
other recommendations.
So that first one was kind of helpful,
mentioned about wheel colliders.
Let' see what the second option says.
So, "Car keeps slipping over.
"The handling is terrible," okay,
"when you go through a
corner, the car flips over."
Let's see what this person say.
"What vehicle physics are you using?
"Are you using wheel colliders at all?
So wheel colliders mentioned again.
"You'll need to provide more information.
"Make a note of centerOfMass."
Well, let's see, so this person
is recommending wheel
colliders and centerOfMass,
and they provide a link.
Let's take a look at centerOfMass first
and see what this does
since it's already linked.
So it says vector3 centerOfMass.
"The center of mass relative
to the transforms origin.
"If you don't set the center of mass,
"it will be calculated automatically
"from all the colliders on the rigidbody."
So maybe we can use the centerOfMass.
I assume maybe the rigidbody
is setting our centerOfMass
a little bit higher
than the actual center of our vehicle.
So we can try and change that.
There's a little example here.
Set centerOfMass this way.
Let me try and play around with that.
Let's see, so center of mass.
They mentioned wheel colliders.
So actually on the documentation,
I can also just search
what I'm looking for.
So if I go to the top-right,
there's this search scripting option here.
I'll type in wheel collider.
Let's see, it's searching.
Oh, okay.
Look at that second option, WheelCollider:
a special collider for vehicle wheels.
That seems pretty useful.
So, "Wheel colliders are used
to model vehicle wheels."
Well, that will probably help a lot.
So let's see what happens first.
So we have these wheels.
If I select the vehicle,
I can actually select
each individual wheel
and you can actually see
they're all children objects
of our player.
So I'll select this first wheel
and I'm going to disable
this Mesh Collider
by unchecking that box
and now there's no collider on this wheel.
You see if I put it back,
so that looks to be a
pretty large problem.
So our wheels are not perfectly circle
so they have these edges on them.
So our wheel will actually
roll on to one of these edges
and these edges might actually
catch on to the ground here.
So that is probably causing
our vehicle to flip over.
So I'll disable this Mesh Collider
and I'll add a component
and look for a wheel collider.
Oh, look at that.
So we do have a component
called a Wheel Collider.
So what if I click this?
Okay, so it's kind of
like a perfect circle.
It's a little too large
for what we're looking for
so let's see, maybe if we
change the radius a bit.
Look too large, maybe
like somewhere kinda,
that looks okay for now.
It's still off-center so that's a problem,
so we'll actually just change
the Y values on the center.
Drag it up a little bit so that looks...
It could be a little smaller,
so I'll actually just gonna
change this value manually,
so I'll type .4.
Still a little high.
Let's see.
If I do .39, we're just a touch smaller.
.14.
It's aa little bit off.
Let's see, maybe if we just
move the Y up a little bit
to .15.
So that look's pretty good.
Pretty close to the wheel itself.
Cool, so we'll collapse
this Mesh Collider.
We're not using it anyways.
So we have this Wheel Collider on.
So I'm actually just going
to apply that Wheel Collider
onto all of our wheels.
So I select the second wheel
and then I Shift and
left-click on the last wheel.
So now all of our wheels are selected.
I can disable the Mesh Collider.
Add a component
and we'll find that Wheel Collider again.
I believe our values were .39 on radius
and then .15 on center.
So I'll just make sure that's correct.
Cool, so first wheel .39, .15,
.39, .15, cool.
So let's see
what happens now that we
have our new wheel colliders.
Look at that!
So out vehicle doesn't stutter anymore.
It's going very fast
and we just toppled over.
So it kind of works.
Our vehicle does a little
bit of a swimming motion
and it's very easy to tip over.
So, at least now we
have the movement down,
but we want to definitely
change how easy it can flip.
Now, that flipping problem
is actually probably caused
by that center of mass
issue that we were having.
And we looked up in the scripting
API in our documentation.
It had some tips about center of mass.
So if we head back to the internet
and I just looked up unity
how to lower our vehicle center of mass.
So we have that link
to the documentation that we had before,
but there's also this
Unity Answers problem here.
So what if I select this one?
So it says here that
they're making a script.
The driving is working,
but whenever they turn hard left or right,
it just starts going on two wheels.
So they don't know if
it's the center of mass
or a problem with the wheel colliders.
"Our wheel colliders definitely work."
You can see here that they've
actually posted a snippet
of their centerOfMass.
That's what the COM stands for.
So this person recommends,
"The easiest way to do this
is add a child empty object
"called centerOfMass.
"Then in your script, set the
empty object's local position
"to the rigid body's center of mass.
"So then we can make it adjustable
"and the script that sets
"that center of mass can be reused."
"Make sure to use that localPosition."
Okay, interesting.
So the thing they recommend to do
is actually create a centerOfMass object
as a child of this player, this vehicle.
So I'm going to right-click on Player
and we're going to create an empty,
and I'll name this game
object, Center of Mass.
So now we have this empty game object
where we can actually
control the center of mass.
Now in my PlayerController script,
is where I'll actually need
to set that center of mass.
So I'll open that up.
So we already have the player's rigidbody.
And according to that person's suggestion,
we can actually just
get the center of mass.
So, let's see when I start my game,
if I get the player rigidbody.
Let's see if I just type center,
Oh, there's centerOfMass.
You can reset centerOfMass.
So now I can actually
get the center of mass
of my rigidbody
and I actually want to set this
to the centerOfMass that we have.
Think actually I'll need to
get that game object first
so let me do this.
Since I need to actually
assign this in Unity,
I can actually use SerializeField.
And in fact, I don't need
to even use the word private
because all of our variables
are private by default.
The cool thing with SerializeField
is now I can actually set a reference
for that centerOfMass game
object without using public.
So I can just say GameObject.
We'll call this centerOfMass.
So now we have that game
object that we're making
so we need to get the center
of mass's actual position,
the transform.position.
And so now, what's happening
is we're actually setting
the rigidbody's center of mass
to the position of the
center of mass object
that we made in our game.
In Unity, one last thing I need to do
is just like that player object,
you can see Center of Mass.
There's no game object referenced.
You can actually take
the child game object
and drop it onto the player.
So now if I test this out.
Let's see, so now our center
of mesh will be lower.
Now our speed doesn't really move.
That doesn't really work.
Let's see, what if we
just like change this,
I don't know, 40,000?
Double it again.
Now I press play.
Doesn't really move.
Let's see, maybe there's a problem
with the actual center of mass.
I see, the center of
mass is in the ground.
That doesn't really work,
so let's move it to like
the bottom of the car.
It's typically where the center
of a vehicle's mass would be.
Now if we press play,
okay, it's a little forward heavy.
Let's move that up a little bit
and move it maybe towards the back?
Oh, there you go.
That is a lot of force we're applying.
Oh, look at that, but we don't flip over.
That's cool.
So originally, in fact,
if I select the Player,
our center of mass was
somewhere around here,
actually where these
arrows are coming from.
So using the center of mass game object,
I moved it a little to the back
and a little bit down to
make it a bit more accurate
as to where the center of mass would be.
Now in our player, we're
still moving too fast.
What if I sent this back to 20,000 again?
We test this.
So it doesn't really work, maybe 30,000?
That way, we're not
accelerating very fast,
as fast as 40,000, but we're still moving.
There we go.
So it looks like there's a small issue
where the vehicle gets stuck.
Let me just, I'm just
gonna move this vehicle.
So what's probably happening
is the wheels are actually
clipping into the ground
so that's where it gets stuck.
So if I press play, the
vehicle, because of gravity,
will fall to the ground, and there you go.
Now it's much smoother as I drive around.
And there we go flying off the screen.
So still too much horsepower.
Let's just bring it back
down to 20,000 again.
And still not enough.
So somewhere between 20,000 and 30,000
is probably a good number.
We'll say 25,000 for now
and see if that works.
So that looks a little bit better.
We can do a few things
like we could actually change the mass
of our vehicle to be even more.
So instead of 1,000, we set it 2,000
so that flip should
definitely happen way less.
We actually applied too mass
so the force isn't enough to move it
so you can change a couple
of different things.
You can change the mass.
You can change the horsepower
and you can change the actual
location of the center of mass
and that will make it easier
to move your vehicle around.
So play around with those
different variables.
So what you're gonna do is
on your vehicles, you're going to select
all of the different wheels,
disable those Mesh Colliders,
add a new component
for the Wheel Collider,
make sure that radius lines up
with those wheels as best as possible,
and then maybe move the center
so that it's actually
the center of the wheels.
You can then create a
new empty game object
called centerOfMass.
Make sure you make it as a
child game object of the player.
So you right-click on
the Player game object
in the hierarchy, go down to Create Empty.
Then it will create the center of mass
right at the center of the vehicle.
If you head into your
development environment,
you can then create a new
variable called centerOfMass,
so that's the game object that we made,
and we'll use SerializeField
so we can actually inside it.
So in our PlayerController script,
we need to add that centerOfMass
by getting that game object.
We can use SerializeField
so that we can actually get the reference
of this center of mass in our inspector.
Then we need to actually
assigned the rigidbody's
center of mass to to the same position
as the centerOfMass game object we made.
So that in Unity, when we
select our player game object,
in the Player Controller Script,
the Center of Mass reference pops up.
We can just click and
drag the center of mass
game object we made
onto the center of mass,
and then we can play around
with the horsepower, the mass,
and the actual position
of the center of mass
to see how our vehicle moves.
One thing to take note of,
while we're using centerOfMass,
and we're using these wheel colliders,
this is not the proper way
that we should be moving these vehicles.
We should, in fact actually,
be using forces and rotation
on the wheels themselves
to move our vehicles.
So if I play my game,
we take a look at our scene view.
So if I play our game
and I move the vehicle down the roads,
not really moving, but you can
see that the vehicle's wheels
aren't actually turning and rotating,
which is what they would
actually do in real life.
So to make this little bit more accurate,
we would then start rotating these wheels
and actually using the
force of that rotation.
Four things that might help,
definitely check out the documentation,
Unity Answers, and the Unity forums
to see what centerOfMass does,
and to see what our wheel colliders do,
and get a better understanding
of how you can use them.
Now it's your turn.