(text thrums)
- [Instructor] Now our objects
are all spawning using our
game manager, and every second,
you'll see a different
object being created.
Now, you can see over on our hierarchy
that we have all of
these different objects
that are continually being
produced and not being destroyed,
so we'll need to destroy
them in two different ways,
so we'll actually get a register
for when we actually click
on one of these different
objects to delete it,
but then also, we need to destroy it
whenever it gets off of
what the player can see.
Now that we're in our target script,
we're going to add in a new method.
In this case, we're going
to override a method
that Unity already has made for us,
which is really handy,
so if we private void,
now we can type OnMouseUp,
or we can type OnMouseDown.
I'll also type in OnMouseUp
just so you can see it.
Now, because this
actually happens so often
in different games and
in different project,
Unity has already made a method to detect
whenever your mouse is
inside of a collider
of an object and you click down,
or if you let go of your click,
it will then fire off an event
that will then immediately use
whatever lines of code
are inside of this block.
Similarly for when we did key presses,
when you press the space bar down
or you let go of the space
bar, you could detect that,
and then you could fire
off a line of code.
In this case, we don't
have to program any of that
because we can just use these
functions that already exist.
I'll get rid of OnMouseUp,
and I'll just use OnMouseDown for now,
and so when the mouse is down
inside one of our objects,
we will then destroy that game object.
Just to test our OnMouseDown, let's see,
if we play our game,
you can see the boxes going up in the air,
I clicked in the wrong place.
One's gone, two, three,
four,
five.
And now you can see,
we can delete them when we click on them,
however, they're still getting created,
and they're not being removed
when they actually
leave the player's view.
Helpfully, in our project,
we actually already have a
empty game object created
called a sensor, and it has a box collider
already applied to it that has a trigger,
so in our target script,
we can actually use the
OnTriggerEnter method,
since the sensor is the only thing
that has a trigger applied to it.
And then when one of our objects
enters the trigger for that
sensor, we can destroy it.
One thing you might've noticed, too,
when we were playing our game,
is that the boxes were
spawning a little bit too low,
so fortunately, since we saved
the Y spawn position as a variable,
if we just move up the boxes a little bit,
maybe to, let's call a negative two,
now you can see when we test our game,
our boxes should spawn
a little bit higher,
and then, when they run into the collider,
they get removed when
they enter the trigger.
One thing you might notice
in our target script
is in our overridden variables,
you'll see the private keyword,
however, in our custom methods,
you'll see that we don't
use the private keyword.
A really nice thing about
scripts is, in fact,
if we don't state that
something is private or public,
it'll automatically
actually make our variables,
if they're global, or our methods private.
What you're gonna do is,
in your target script,
you're going to create an
OnMouseDown overridden method,
and in that method, you're going
to destroy the game object,
so that way, when our mouse
is inside the collider
of one of our objects, when
we click our mouse down,
it'll actually destroy that game object,
and similarly, you'll create
an OnTriggerEnter method
where, when one of the game objects runs
into the sensor at the
bottom of our scene,
it'll destroy that game object, too.
Now it's your turn.
(text thrums)