(electronic tone)
- [Instructor] We have
all of our prefab set up
so they're randomly spawned
in different positions.
They have different forces applied to them
so that they fly up the screen.
Now we're going to use
a list to keep track
of all of these objects to spawn them.
But instead of using a spawn manager,
we're actually going to
create a game manager,
since we're also going
to use the game manager
to control the states of our game later.
In your project hierarchy, if
you click the create button
and create an empty for
creating an empty game object,
we'll rename the scheme
object as game manager.
And then we need a game manager script
to be able to actually use it.
So in our scripts folder,
if we right-click,
create a C# script and
call it game manager.
We'll now apply our game manager script
to our game manager object,
and you can see that it's applied.
A cool thing you might notice is
that on the script, instead
of having the little C# icon
on it, it actually has a gear icon.
So in Unity, it actually tries to help you
in a lot of ways, and in this case,
because game manager is a script
that people use very often,
Unity actually creates a
special icon just for it,
so then that way, you know
that this is actually something
that we'll use to control
the different settings
for our game.
If we open up the game manager script,
now we're going to do something similar
in our game manager script to get the list
of all the objects we're gonna use.
So we're going to public so
we can apply the references.
But instead of using an array,
we can use a very similar
data structure called a list.
And then with a list, we actually need
to give it the type of something,
so we'll create game object
and we'll call this targets.
Now a list is extremely similar
to an array, so if we were
to create our own array,
we could call it game
object and then targets two.
And you can see I actually
misspelled game objects.
So the notation is very similar,
but with the list itself,
we can actually pass it in the
type of thing that we want,
versus with an array, we
have to tell the array
what that thing is before
we make the array itself.
Lists and arrays have slightly
different functionality
in terms of the ways that they work.
Overall, lists and arrays have
slightly different
functionality, so there are times
where a list is more useful than an array,
but for the purpose of this project,
we'll just use a list for now
so that we can kind of get used to it
and see how it works
and how similar it is.
Now when we save, when we go into Unity,
you can see our game manager script.
It has the name of the targets.
We can create a size, very similar
to how made a size for our array.
So we'll set this to four.
And we have four elements
that we can give it.
So we'll give it the bad object,
the good object, the second
one, and the third one.
So what you're gonna do, is
in your project hierarchy,
you're going to create a new empty object,
call it game manager.
You're going to create a new
script called game manager,
apply that script to
the game manager object.
In your game manager script,
create a new public list
of game objects, and then
in your game manager,
just make sure that you apply the prefabs
onto each of the different elements.
Now it's your turn.
(electronic tone)