(electronic music)
- [Instructor] Now, the
first thing that we'll need
for this little game is three objects
that we're gonna collect
and then a bad object to avoid.
So we're going to go
into our project window.
We're going to, under our assets folder,
expand our course library
and then in our course library,
we're going to expand our props.
Now you can see we have a
bunch of different options here
from bad things we don't
wanna collide with.
We have different balls we can use.
We have food.
There's other types of things.
So I think I'm just going to use
some of these other objects here.
So I like the look of all
of these different crates
so I'm gonna go and drag
them into my hierarchy.
And you can kinda see they're
stacking on top of each other
so we'll just go and
we'll use our move tool
and we'll just drag them onto
our scene so we can see them.
And then we need a bad prop to use
so we'll go into props, bad
and we'll just click and drag.
I'll use a skull as one of my bad props.
That way it's very clear
which ones are good.
All of these different crates over here
and then we have our skull
which we definitely don't wanna press.
Now, we're going to
rename all of our props
so that way it's easier to manage them.
So we'll name the skull and
we'll just make this very simple
so we'll call this Bad 1
for the first bad prop.
And our crate, we'll name this Good 1,
so this is the first one.
We have Good 2
and then our last cube will be Good 3.
Now on all of our props,
we actually need rigid
bodies and box colliders
because this game is gonna
be a bunch of objects
being thrown up in the
air and then falling
and we need the physics for that.
And then we need colliders
because we're actually going to
add triggers to each
of these boxes as well.
So I'm going to select the first box
and then I'll select the
last item on the list
and I'm just going to add components
so I'll add a box collider
so hopefully it works
on all of them properly
and then I'll add a rigid body.
So now we have box colliders
and rigid bodies applied to all of them.
Just make sure they work properly
so you can see the box looks pretty close.
Cube also looks good.
That one looks good.
Let's see what happens with the bad.
Yeah, pretty well lined up.
Now, what we're gonna do
is in our assets folder,
we're going to right-click on it
and create a new folder
and this will be for our scripts.
And then in our scripts folder,
we're just going to make
a script called target.
And then we're going to select
all of our different objects as well
and they'll all use the same
target script in general
so we don't need to get
very fancy with this.
So now you can see they all
have the target script applied.
Now, in our assets folder,
we'll create a new
folder for our pre-fabs.
Now we're gonna take each
of our different objects
and we'll drag them into
our pre-fabs folder.
Make sure you create original pre-fabs.
And now, since we have
all of our pre-fabs,
I'll just go and delete
all of these objects in our scene now
'cause I don't think we'll
need to edit them much later
so delete and now we're good to go.
So what you're gonna do
is you're going to go into
your course library folder,
underneath props, you can pick a bad prop
that you're gonna use for your game
and then choose three other props.
They can be balls.
They can be food.
They can be any other kind
of prop that you wanna use.
Make sure on all of the props
you add a rigid body
and a collider
and then just make sure
that the collider is properly lined up
with the actual object you're using.
In our project window, create
a new folder for your scripts
and create a target script
that you'll then apply
to each of your different
objects on your scene.
Once you have the box collider,
the rigid body and your script applied,
create your pre-fabs folder,
drag and drop all of
your different objects
into your pre-fabs folder.
Create original pre-fabs
and then you can see all of
the different pre-fabs here
with all of the components applied.
So, now it's your turn.
(electronic music)