(logo chimes)
- [Instructor] So, we have each of our
different prefabs
created and we've applied
our components to them.
So now we're actually going to use
our target script to control
the force that they move in the air,
the random position that they start
off at the bottom of the scene,
and then torque to be
able to rotate the object.
If you double-click on your target script
now with our target script open
we're going to create some variables.
So we're going to create
a private variable
for our rigid body
so that we can just find
it using get component.
And we'll call this targetRb since
each one of our different objects
are the different targets
we're trying to hit.
And our start method we're going to take
targetRb and we'll set it to be
the component on our object
which is our rigid body.
Now that we have our rigid body component,
we need to apply a force on our object
so that when it spawns it moves up
in our scene so that it can fall down.
So using our target rigid body
we're going to add a force
in this case our force is going
to be in the up direction
and we'll multiply this
by a random value for now
so we're actually going to use
our random range method
and we'll set it just to task,
we'll use 12 as the lowest
value that it could be
and 16 as the highest.
We actually want this
force applied instantly
so we'll use a force mode
and we'll use our impulse.
Another thing that we wanna do
is we actually want this object to
rotate and move as it
gets through our scene.
So we're gonna use our rigid body again,
this time we're actually
going to use torque.
So add torque and so torque will actually
apply the force for our objects to rotate.
In this case we just need the directions
that the torque will be applied in
so we'll use random ranges for
our x, our y, and our z.
So we're randomly generate a value
that it will rotate in
say negative ten and ten,
so that's on the x.
We need to generate another random value
I'm just going to actually reuse this bit
of code so I'm actually
just gonna copy this.
I'll paste it into our Y value
and then I'll paste it into our Z value
so our x, our y, and our z
are all calculating
different random values
between negative ten and ten.
Again, we want this
force applied instantly
so I'll actually use another force mode.
And then we want to set the position
of our object randomly on our x.
Finally, what we're gonna do is
we're going to create a random
place for our different object to spawn.
So we're going to get the position
of our current object and we'll set
this to be a new vector three
and for the x it'll be a random range
so I'll try and keep it between
negative four and four.
This way it stays between the
left and right side of our screen
for our y value, we'll set it to
something like negative six
that way it spawns underneath the scene
and then for our z value
we can set it to zero.
Now if we wanna test
and see how this looks,
we can actually drag our prefabs
into our hierarchy and it'll randomly
create those effects.
So it has a random position,
it's got the random force applied.
Now one little bit of clarity
that we can actually add,
so since we're not actually using
the z value here,
we can actually remove this
and since we're not really moving
anything on the z in general,
in this case it'll set the
x to be a random range,
the Y will be negative six
underneath what our player can see
and our z is always just gonna be zero.
So what you're gonna do is
in your target script you're going to
create a rigid body variable,
you're gonna get the reference
for that rigid body component,
now that you have your
rigid body component
add a force in the up direction
using a random strength between 12 an 16
and make sure that you apply
the force with an impulse.
In our next line of code
we're going to add torque to apply
rotation to our object
and we're just going to use
randomly generated values for all
the different x, y, and z.
Then we're going to set the position
of our object to be a random range
on our x and just below what our player
can see on the y.
Now it's your turn.
(logo chimes)