- [Narrator] So, we've got
makings of a solid foundation
for a game so when we press play you can
see all the different
objects thrown into the air.
When they get past the
sensor bar at the bottom
they get removed, if we click
on them they also get removed.
In this lesson we also learned about
using or 2D
verses or 3D view.
In this case since we're playing in 2D
it's a lot easier if we just look at our
entire view through the 2D one.
We learned how to also apply Torque
to the rigid bodies of our objects
in our target script.
We also created a Game Manager object
instead of a Bond Manager, because we'll
be using this actually control the state
of our game as we add more to it.
In our Game Manager script
we learn how to use a list
in place of a raise
to be able to get different objects.
We reused our ienumerator on co-routine
and inside actually used a
While statement to be able
to control while something is happening
to keep iterating over our blocks of code
and keep doing them over and over again.
And then finally we learned how to use
a new method our "OnMouseDown",
so that whenever we get our mouse click we
can actually immediately
know when it's over
one of our objects and
we can destroy the game
object as a result.
In our next lesson we'll
make this game look
just a little bit better
by adding in some effects
as well as keeping track of the score,
whenever we click on one
of these different objects.
See you on the next lesson.