- [Instructor] Another cool feature
that a lot of car simulators have
is a display of the RPM,
or revolutions per minute.
The tricky part is figuring
out how to calculate it.
First, what we need to do is create
a new text area for our RPM,
so in my canvas,
if I left click on that
little dropdown arrow,
so we have the speedometer here,
I need to right click on Canvas,
and I'll create another UI TextMeshPro.
Now, it's somewhere off in the distance.
Let's see if we can get...
There we go.
So, you can see it's in the
center of our canvas here,
and we need to actually
move it to the top left.
About here.
I'm actually going to set the anchor first
so it's in the top left, then let's see.
What line is that at on the Y?
X is 135, so I think if we just
move this over, there you
go, so it's all lined up,
so that looks nice and clean.
And, here, we'll change this to RPM.
To avoid that problem we had
with the speed before with Wrapping,
we're going to set this to Disabled,
and now we can get our RPM.
Let me make sure that I rename
this element to be "RPM."
Now, I need to actually create
another variable for this,
so in my PlayerController script,
right after the SpeedometerText,
I will create a new
SeralizeField: TextMeshProUGUI.
We'll call this RPMText,
and I need to make sure that
I set the RPM as a reference,
so in Unity, if I select my player,
we'll drop this RPMText element down
into the Rpm Text.
So, now, we have the RPM text,
but we need to actually calculate the RPM,
so let's see what we can do.
So, the Internet will be
another helpful resource
here once again so, here,
we need to calculate the
RPM of our vehicle in Unity,
so we have all of these different options.
We'll check out this
Unity Answers question.
So, this person is making a speed limiter,
wants to do this through
wheelcollider.rpm.
Hmm, that could be interesting.
Problem is we would have to
get a reference to one
of our wheel colliders
and then see what that does.
Let's see what this person says.
If you want to get the speed,
you should know the
circumference of your wheel,
multiply it, okay...
Let's see, what are they doing down here?
Speedometer, wheel radius...
This seems a little too complicated.
We're just going to maybe do a bit simpler
of a whole calculation than this,
but this is a generally helpful start.
You can see they're actually
doing the conversions
from the RPM to the speed,
which is kinda cool.
So, in order to get our RPM,
I'll make another variable,
and just so we can see what it's doing,
we will make it a serialized
variable called "float rpm."
So, now, we actually have
to do some calculations
for our RPM in our Update method.
So, that person used RPM to get to speed,
so we can use our speed to get to our RPM,
so we'll make our RPM variable,
and RPM is generally pretty large number
compared to our actual speed,
so if you're going somewhere around,
I don't know, like 80 miles per hour,
maybe get like 3,000 RPM or so,
so we'll just say speed,
and, in this case, we'll just
create our own little formula,
and just kind of show you a
cool symbol that you can use,
so if I type Shift on the number five,
I get this percent symbol,
and just for the sake of
seeing what it looks like,
so "speed percent 30."
So, the percent symbol is a
special kind of operator in C#,
and in programming in general,
called the modulus operator,
or what you may be more familiar with,
the remainder operator.
And so, this means that we are actually
dividing speed by 30
and then it will actually
give us the remainder value,
so if speed were to be 30,
and then we divide by 30,
we actually get a zero.
If we divide speed, which is 31,
divide that by 30, we actually get a one.
And so, this is just kind of a cool way
that we can kind of wrap
our numbers all the way
from zero to 29.
So let's save, and in fact,
we actually need to set this RPM
and our RPM text, so we do "RPMText.
"SetText...
"RPM...
"Plus RPM."
So, now, we save, let's
check out our project.
See what happens when we press Play.
So, now, we should just
see it go from zero
to 29 and then it goes
back, so that's cool.
However, 29 is definitely
not a very high RPM,
so we'll make this a little bit cleaner.
We'll actually just wrap
this entire little equation
with parentheses so, that way,
this operation happens first,
and then we multiply this times 40.
Let's save, now let's see.
Let's see what kinda numbers we get.
Okay.
It's kinda as if like
when you're going through
each of the different speeds.
You're actually kind of
shifting gears in a way,
resetting the RPM back
down every time, cool.
So what you're gonna do is create
a new Text Object for the RPM.
Make sure to position it in the top left.
Make sure to disable Wrapping.
And then, in your PlayerController script,
make sure to create a
new RPMText variable,
as well as an RPM variable.
Head down to your Update method
where you're going to create
this little formula here,
this little equation to calculate the RPM,
and then just make sure to set
RPMText to have that value,
so that, when you test your game in Unity,
you should see that the
RPM goes all the way
to about 1200 and then
it resets back down,
and then it goes back up to 1200 again
as if you're changing gears.
Now, it's your turn.