(electronic noises)
- [Instructor] In this lesson,
you'll attempt to add a
speedometer and RPM display,
for your vehicle, in Prototype 1.
And, in doing so, you'll learn the process
of doing online research,
when trying to implement new features,
and troubleshoot bugs in your projects.
As you'll find out, adding a new feature
is very rarely as simple
as it initially seems.
You inevitably run into
unexpected complications
and errors that usually require
a little online research.
So, in this lesson, we'll learn how to do
some online research, so
that we can do it on our own,
for our projects.
Now, one thing that'll
set our driving game
apart from our driving simulator,
is by adding something like a speedometer,
to be able to actually track
the speed of our vehicle,
much like you would see in a car itself.
If we're going to implement a speedometer,
the first thing we have to do
is make the vehicle accelerate
and decelerate more like a real car,
which uses forces, as opposed
to the translate method.
Because of the fact that translate
will actually move our
vehicle at a constant speed,
we'll need to use forces and
rigid bodies on our vehicle,
to make it move at different speeds,
by applying different
forces onto the vehicle,
to make it speed up and slow down.
So, open up your Prototype 1 project.
And when Prototype 1 is open,
we're going to make a
backup of our project,
because we're going to
change some of our code.
So, in the top left of Unity,
go to the Assets dropdown,
and Export Package.
Now, I'm going to export this package
directly to my Create with Code folder.
So, I'll call this Prototype 1 Complete.
Now, I'll make sure to save.
So, now that we've saved our Prototype 1,
if you remember, on our player object,
we have this Player Controller Script.
Which is how we actually move our vehicle
through the scene, using
that translate method.
So, I need to actually go
into my Scripts folder,
and open up PlayerController.
Now, in my PlayerController script,
I have the transform.Translate method,
where I move the vehicle.
But I need to use physics
and forces to do so.
Instead of using transform.Translate.
So, I'm actually going
to create a new variable
for our rigidbody.
And now I need to actually
assign that rigidbody
when our game starts.
So, now, in our start
method, our playerRB variable
is set to the RigidBody component,
that we have on our actual vehicle.
Now, one thing I wanna do is
I want to actually comment out the speed.
Because I'm going to
create a different variable
for applying the actual force.
So, in case I want to use speed,
and I want to use this translate method,
I'll comment both of those lines out.
So, instead of speed,
I'll make a private float,
called horsePower, and we'll
set that zero, for now.
Since I actually want to
interact with this variable,
I'm going to add that
SerializeField attribute.
So, now I can actually play
around with this variable,
in Unity, even though it's private.
And then, in my update method,
I'm going to use that rigidbody.
I'm going to apply a force,
using the AddForce method.
We want to apply that force
in the forward direction.
We don't actually need
to use Time.deltaTime,
since we're applying forces,
instead of translating something.
I'll multiply it by the
horsePower that we have.
And then we need to
actually control that force.
So, we'll use vertialInput.
So, this line of code
isn't entirely different
from our original line.
In some of our past projects,
we were using AddForces to move things.
So, now is a good opportunity
to try using AddForce again.
So, I make sure I save.
Now, in Unity, you can see
that my PlayerController script
has updated on the Inspector.
So, I'll select that player.
And Horse Power is set to zero.
So, what I'll actually do is
I'm gonna test out this variable.
So, I'm gonna enter Play mode.
And we know zero's not
gonna move it, at all.
So, let's try 10, since
we have about 20 before.
So, we're not really moving,
but we can turn still.
See, what if I just move it to about 100.
Does it move anywhere, no?
Okay, maybe we need more force.
1,000?
Still nothing, let's go even more, 10,000.
Very little movement.
Okay, let's just do, let's say, 20,000.
Oh, there you go.
So, our vehicle moves forward,
but it doesn't actually
move in the direction
that we turn it in.
So, that's frustrating.
Let me make sure that I
actually set this variable,
now that I'm out of Play mode.
And let's try that again
and see what happens.
Yeah, so, the vehicle doesn't move
in the right direction, at all.
It's just always moving forward.
Which could look really cool,
if you're making a drifting game.
But we still want to be
able to turn that vehicle.
So, what did we do wrong?
To help conceptualize the problem here.
So, you can see, right
now, we have the arrows,
for that Move tool.
And, right now, our Move tool
is actually locked into
Global coordinates.
So, we can use this
toggle, in the top left,
to switch between Global and Local.
And so, now, Local should actually turn,
as we turn the vehicle.
So, with the Global coordinates
set up on our Rotation tool,
if I actually rotate this
vehicle left to right,
you can see that it actually is always
still pointing down the road.
If I switch to Local coordinates,
you can actually see, as
I rotate this vehicle,
now the arrow is pointing
wherever the vehicle points.
So, we actually need to figure
out how we can apply forces
according to our Local coordinates.
Luckily, the internet
is our good friend here.
So, in Google, I actually typed in
Unity AddForce in local space.
And you can see all these
different things popped up.
There's actually some Unity
Answers questions here.
So, this is actually our forum,
where users go to ask questions.
And then other users will
actually answer it for them.
And then we also have the Scripting API.
This is actually the
official Unity documentation.
So, you can see here, we
have that AddForce method.
We know that doesn't work, so, let's see.
If we clicked into the topmost result,
the question here says,
AddForce in local space.
And the user asked, how
do you change and AddForce
from Global to Local?
The top reply, from this user,
says to AddRelativeForce
instead of AddForce.
So, we were using AddForce before.
But I don't know what this
AddRelativeForce does.
So, you can see that the
user was trying to point us
in the right direction,
using AddRelativeForce.
Down in the suggestions
for the Scripting API,
AddRelativeForce is
actually one of the options
that we can select, as a result.
Or we can ask Google, once again.
So, Unity AddRelativeForce.
So, this actually brings up that result
for our documentation.
So, you can see, in our
official documentation,
the Description tells
us that it adds a force
to the rigidbody, relative
to its coordinate system.
So, it actually, it's using
that local coordinate system.
So, if I go to my PlayerController script,
if I go down to my update method,
if I just add the word Relative
to AddForce, I can save.
And then I head back into Unity.
And I test my game out in Play mode.
And see, as I turn, I should be moving
in the direction the vehicle is pointing.
So, you can see that works.
Our vehicle is doing some
weird things, at the moment.
That's fine, we'll fix that in a bit.
Oh, we just flipped over.
But, on the up side, our
vehicle isn't just driving
straight down the road, as I turn.
So, using a little bit of
searching, on the internet,
and finding the AddRelativeForce method,
I was able to fix a problem that I had.
So, what you're gonna
do is you're going to
open up Prototype 1, in
the top left of Unity.
If you select the Assets menu option,
go down to Export Package,
you're going to export
a new package, to save as a
backup for your Prototype 1,
since we're going to change it.
You're then going to open up
your PlayerController script.
In your PlayerController script,
you can comment out the
variable for your speed.
And you can comment out the line,
where we are moving the vehicle,
using transform.Translate.
I added a new variable for our horsePower,
that will be applied as a force.
I used that new attribute, SerializeField,
so that I can actually
change this value, in Unity.
I needed to make a new
variable for our rigidbody.
And then I needed to assign that rigidbody
in our start method, using GetComponent,
to find the rigidbody
of our current object.
And then, in our update method,
instead of using transform.Translate,
I used player rigidbody.AddRelativeForce,
to move it in the forward direction,
times the actual force
that we're applying.
And then multiplied that
by our actual input,
so we could control our vehicle
again, using our arrow keys.
So, then, when you test
out your game in Unity,
by entering Play mode,
you can move the vehicle down the road.
And, as you turn it, it
will actually start moving
in the direction it's pointing.
Now it's your turn.
(electronic noises)