(electronic chimes)
- [Instructor] Now that
we have the vehicle
in a semi-drivable state,
let's display the speed
on our user interface.
In order to do so, we
need to add a TextMeshPro
object to our scene, much like
we did with projects before.
So in the hierarchy,
I'm going to right click
in the empty space,
go down to UI,
and go to Text - TextMeshPro.
Since I haven't added TextMeshPro
to this project before,
I'm gonna need to import it.
Now that it's imported, I can exit out,
so now we can see in our
scene we have our vehicle,
but we can see the white outlines
of this TextMeshPro canvas,
so I'm actually going
to select that canvas,
and press F, so now it zooms
out to I can actually see,
very far zoomed out.
So if we get our canvas
in frame here, you can see
our little game world here in the corner,
then we have our TextMeshPro canvas here,
so if I press play you should
see that little New Text
pop up, probably on the
bottom right about there.
So that doesn't look good at all,
so we're gonna have to
actually adjust that.
So first what we're gonna
do is with the actual text,
we're gonna rename this
to our Speedometer,
and we want our speedometer to have
probably a position on the top left,
where our player can see
how fast they're going,
so first I'm actually going to change
the anchors to be the top left,
and now I'm going to move
the text over to that corner,
right about there,
and then for the text, I'll
just say "Speed" for now.
Now if I press play, we should see
speed in the top left corner,
cool, so that looks pretty good.
Not gonna change any of the text for now,
for the fonts or anything like that,
I'm just gonna leave it as is.
In this case, since we just
want to see our speed working,
we're not gonna use a Game Manager script,
I'm actually just going to use
my PlayerController script,
since that's where I can
actually see the speed
that our player's moving at.
So in the PlayerController
script, I actually need to
create a variable for
that TextMeshPro text,
so in fact I actually need
to import that library first,
so at the top of my script,
I add a using statement,
for using TMPro.
So now I can find the TextMeshPro library,
I'm going to create another
serialized variable,
like this GameObject,
this time I actually need the actual text,
so I'll get the TextMeshProUGUI,
and call it speedometerText,
so now that I have this variable,
in Unity I need to make
sure that I actually
attach this text to the speedometer text,
so I'm just going to click
and drag on Speedometer
and drop it in there.
So now we have a reference, and I can
change the text when I need to.
Now the question is, how do we actually
calculate the speed of our vehicle?
Once again we'll head
over to the internet,
and see if anybody has
any questions for us
so I looked up "calculate vehicle speed,"
and one of the first answers
is "how to get car speed,"
that seems like what I'm looking for.
So let's see, this person
has a car that can move,
and they want to get the speed,
'K, so...
Says here so for a car,
speed, in kilometers per hour,
is Speed, so I guess we
need a speed variable again,
we set that to the magnitude,
so we can actually get the velocity
that our rigidbody is moving,
so that's very helpful,
and then in this case
they multiply by 3.6.
That's a pretty good start, so
we can actually just use this
rigidbody.velocity.magnitude,
and velocity will actually
get us the actual velocity,
the speed that our vehicle is moving,
and the magnitude gives us the number.
So that was pretty helpful,
I did notice as I was
going through the results
that there is another result
about a car with wheel colliders,
we do have wheel colliders so let's
just see what this person says.
"Making a simple car driving
game," with a guiText,
cool, that's exactly
what we're trying to do,
"speed displayed doesn't
seem very realistic."
this person has this little formula here.
See what the reply is.
"Simply get the speed
by using" there's that
rigidbody.velocity.magnitude again,
oh, so it returns the
speed in meters per second.
That's what you get when
you're using velocity.
So to get the speed,
in kilometers per hour,
oh, so you multiply by 3.6,
so that's why 3.6 was there.
If you want to get it in miles per hour,
multiply by 2.237, oh okay.
So because, when you're
going from meters per second
to kilometers per hour, you have to do
a little bit of math to
get the proper number,
of how to convert meters per
second to kilometers per hour,
or miles per hour so that's
actually what those numbers are.
"You don't need to do calculations
using wheelcolliders."
Okay, cool, that's pretty helpful!
So since it said we needed to
make speed variable before,
I'm actually going to
un-comment-out our speed variable,
I'm actually going to turn this
into a serialized variable as well.
Since our speed is actually
being calculated now,
I don't actually need
to set it when I start.
Now, in my update method, I
probably want to calculate
my speed after I apply that force,
so if I do speed equals player rigidbody,
.velocity.magnitude,
then we want to times it
by I think it was, 2.237f,
that way our program knows
that that number's a float.
Just for our own sake
if we wanna change it
to kilometers per hour, so
"For kilometers per hour,
"change to 2.237 to 3.6," okay.
So now we're getting that actual speed,
so now we just need to actually
set the text for our speedometer.
So if we do speedometerText.SetText,
we need to make a string so we can
say that this is the speed,
and then we concatenate
the actual speed that we're calculating,
and then just as a nice touch we'll add
another string at the end
to say miles per hour.
So now if I save this, hopefully,
now our speed should
update in the top left
when we play our game.
Okay, well that's very weird, uh.
My speed is moving very
fast, I think I actually
still have my vehicle
set to be very heavy,
change that really quick.
Up 2000, I believe it was 1000 before.
Let's see, so now we play,
and we can move down the road,
and there you go, so you
can see it's changing,
there's a lot of numbers
after the decimal point,
and in fact when we press play,
you can see that, it actually starts
giving us a number value,
because it's falling to the ground.
So that doesn't look great,
also it's kind of small,
we should probably make
that a little bit larger,
but let's fix this problem first,
'cause this looks very weird,
just all these decimals.
So how do we get rid of these decimals?
Well, the decimals happen because
this number is a float,
and to get a round number
we actually need an integer.
So how do we get an integer from a float?
So let's head back over to the internet
and see what it has to say, I looked up
"how to convert float to integer unity,"
the first result that popped
up is this Mathf.RoundToInt,
so "returns f", so that's the float,
"rounded to the nearest
integer," let's see.
Ah, so float f, so that's
the number we're passing in,
and then it gives you back f
rounded to the nearest integer.
Okay, so it looks like this
is how you would use it, so,
Mathf.RoundToInt, so then
you put in the float,
and then it gives you 10.
Okay, hmm.
So MathF.RoundToInt.
Well, let's see if that works on this
little formula that we have here,
so I'm actually just going to
apply this here, so let's
see, MathF.RoundToInt.
Then I guess we just wanna put
this entire number in here?
So now if we save,
so now, we should just get whole numbers,
there you go, just says
zero, could probably
make that text box a little
bigger, there you go,
now it's just whole round numbers,
so that's good, so that works great.
We'll fix that issue with the
size later, but that works.
For a fun little fact, if you
remember, a few lessons ago,
we were talking about different
keywords you could use
on variables, things like
const, read only, and static,
you can actually see we have a
const variable here, for our turn speed,
and this is actually, down here,
where we're calculating our speed,
a case where you can
actually see a static class.
Actually in fact, up here as well.
And so if you remember, in
cases like our rigidbody,
we have to actually create a
variable for that rigidbody,
and then assign it to something,
but for things like input or for math,
we don't actually need
to instantiate anything
to use these classes.
That's because they're actually static.
And so static allows us
to use different classes
without having to create an instance,
like playerRb for our rigidbody.
So what we're gonna do is in Prototype 1,
you're going to add a new
TextMeshPro text to your project
by right clicking in the hierarchy,
going down to UI, create
a Text - TextMeshPro,
it'll prompt you if you
want to import TextMeshPro
because we haven't used
it in this project yet,
once you import that just go to your text,
rename it Speedometer so
we know what it's used for,
you can ever change the placeholder text,
reposition it so it's in the top left,
and after you've set up your text,
go into your PlayerController script,
you're going to add a new line at the top
to use the TextMeshPro library,
you can un-comment-out
your speed variable,
and you can actually just
make it a serialized field,
without any value assigned to it,
you're going to create another variable
for the speedometer text itself,
and then in your update method,
you're going to write
two new lines of code,
one to set the speed
to a rounded value from float to int,
by calculating the actual velocity
that the player is moving,
and then you have to
multiply it by this 2.237f,
for the actual miles per hour.
So once you've calculated
that entire thing,
you're just going to
set the speedometer text
so that it actually tells
you what the speed is.
After you set that text, just make sure to
pop back into Unity,
on your player object,
make sure you drag that speedometer text
down to the speedometer text here
in your PlayerController script,
so that when you play your game,
you should see that the
speed starts updating.
Now it's your turn!
(electronic chimes)