- We've got a lot of great functionality
in this game now for this prototype.
So we have the player that spawns.
We have our enemy.
We have the power-up that we can pick up.
We have the indicator and then
we have the timer that counts down,
so we bounce off of all of these enemies.
And with every new enemy wave we spawn
new power-ups.
On top of that we learned
some really useful
coding concepts.
We learned about For-loops
to keep control over the number of times
we want something to execute.
In this case our instantiate method
so that we can spawn
different numbers of enemies
every time the player defeats one.
In order to actually increment the number
of enemies we want to spawn,
we learned how to use the (++) or
incremental operator,
so then that way we
can increase I plus one
every time this For-Loop runs.
We also created our own custom method.
This time with a parameter to pass in,
so then that way we could keep track of
the number of enemies to spawn
based on our wave number.
And then in our update method
we learned how to use FindObjectsOfType
so that we could get any object
with a type of our enemies script.
So then we could actually get the
number of enemies that are in our scene.
Last but not least with
the end of the prototype
we've learned a lot of
really useful things,
like using I enumerators and co-routines
so in that way we can actually
have a countdown timer
for our power-up
so then eventually it goes away.
We learned how to use physical materials
so that way we can have a bouncy effect
so when these different spheres run into
each other they'll
bounce off of each other
even more.
We learned how to really
use camera control.
And learned about child game objects to
control this camera around a focal point
in our scene.
And then we learned how to use vector math
to actually control the direction that
these enemies are moving towards
so that they eventually
run into the player.
With that we've made it to
the end of our prototype
and we'll see you in the next project.