- All of the pieces of our prototype
are functioning perfectly.
The player, the enemy, the power up.
All flawless.
The problem is that we can
only experience this
functionality very briefly,
because as soon as you
knock the first enemy off,
that's it.
The game's over.
The player wins.
If I know these enemy
spheres like I think I do,
they shouldn't go down without a fight,
so by the end of this lesson,
whenever all enemies are destroyed,
a new wave of enemies will spawn
with one more enemy than the wave before,
gradually increasing
the game's difficulty.
In order to spawn all of these enemies,
we'll have to call the instantiate method
a whole bunch of times.
What you could do is just
write that line of code
over and over again,
but as you probably guessed,
that's not the best way to do it.
Instead, we'll use
something called a for-loop,
which will loop through some code
for as many times as we specify.
The really great thing about for-loops,
as opposed to just writing
the same line of code
over and over again,
is that you can use a variable
to dynamically change the number of times
the for-loop will run.
So in the first wave,
we'll make the for-loop run
once to create one enemy.
In the second wave,
it will run twice to spawn two enemies.
In the third wave,
we can have it run three times
to spawn three enemies and so on.
So to make all that happen,
I'll see you in Unity.