(unity signature)
- [Instructor] Our game
is almost complete now.
So, when we pick up
the powerup, we can hit
the enemy off the scene and then
it will generate new
enemies, but the problem is,
we only have one powerup and
so when our powerup goes away
we have no way of actually
defeating these enemies unless
we outsmart them by getting them
to fall off of the platform.
So we're going to create
a new powerup every time
we start a new wave.
In our spawn manager script,
we're actually going to declare
a new public game object for our powerup.
And now we need to make sure
that this reference is assigned
in our editor.
So now in Unity, if we select
our spawn manager, you can see
that we have an empty game
object for our powerup prefab
so make sure you go down to
your project window under Assets
in your Prefabs folder.
Drag the power up into
that slot instead of using
the one in the scene and then back
in our spawn manager script,
in our line of code where
we keep track of when all
of the enemies are gone
and create new enemies, we'll instantiate
a new powerup prefab.
Fortunately, we created a
method to generate random spawn
positions so we can just use that again
and then we'll just make
sure to set the rotation
of our powerup prefab.
One thing that you could
do just to clean this up
a bit more is you could just
make a spawn powerup method
if you wanted to and then
every time you wanted to create
a new powerup, you can just
call that method instead,
but, for now, this one
line of code is fine.
And then just to test and see
that our powerup spawning
works properly, we'll delete
our powerup from the scene,
play our game, and now we spawn
the enemy, and we didn't spawn a powerup
so that's a problem.
I actually have -- well
that's pretty lucky
but that wasn't exactly
what we wanted to do.
Let's see what we did
wrong in our spawn manager.
Ahh, so when we start the game,
we create a new enemy wave
but we don't actually create a new powerup
so we'll take this line
of code and we'll copy it
so that in our start method we also create
a new random position
for our powerup prefab.
So now in our game,
if we try and get to our powerup.
Let's see, can we make it.
Enemy fell off anyways, got the powerup.
Another powerup spawns and there you go.
And then both enemies fall.
And then three enemies and two powerups.
So, what you're gonna do is
in your spawn manager script
you're going to create
a new public game object
for your powerup prefab.
In your start method,
you're going to instantiate
a new powerup prefab and you're gonna use
the generate spawn position
method once again so we get
a random position for
our powerup and then also
in our update method when
we create a new enemy wave
we'll create another
powerup so that we can use
it in case we need it.
So, now it's your turn.
(unity signature)