(upbeat tone)
- [Instructor] Now we can
control the enemies spawning
whenever they all leave the scene.
So what we're gonna do is
actually increase the
number of enemies every time
we defeat a wave.
So, we'll have one spawn
and then we can have two spawn
and three, and so on.
In our Spawn Manager
Script we're going to use
a variable to control the actual
number of enemies in the wave.
So, we'll make a Public Variable
so we can see what it does again,
make it an Integer, and then
we'll call it Wave Number,
and we'll set it to one in the beginning,
and then we'll actually use
this wave number to dictate
how many enemies should spawn after
we defeat every enemy.
In our If Statement, since
this is where we know
when enemies are defeated,
this is actually where we'll
increment our wave number.
So we'll change our spawn enemy wave
and start to be wave number,
so this will spawn one
enemy at the beginning.
Now, when we've defeated
all of the enemies
we'll set wave number and
we'll use that plus plus, this time.
So now when the enemies are all defeated,
it will increase wave number by one,
so now wave number should be two.
And then if we change the
enemies to spawn parameter,
to be a wave number here,
so then it should spawn
two enemies afterwards.
So, now if we test our game,
we should see one enemy
spawn; there we go.
And then if we hit this
enemy off, two enemies spawn.
Then see if we can hit both.
Oh, we have one.
And the last one
will go off and then do we get three?
And there you go.
So, now in your spawn manager script,
you're going to add another variable
to keep track of the wave number.
So we'll set it to one
and we'll make it public so
we can see what it's doing.
In our Start Method, change
enemy wave to wave number
and then in our Update Method,
where we can actually keep track
of when we hit the point
where all the enemies
are off the scene and we create a new one,
we'll increment wave number
by one here and then we'll
spawn a new enemy wave using
the incremented number.
Now it's your turn.
(upbeat tone)