(synthetic chime)
- [Male] Now the player
can pick up this power-up
and then it'll open up the
power-up indicator that will show
when we have our power-ups
so we can blast our opponents
away off of the environment.
It's still a little bit too easy,
so we're going to introduce
a bit more challenge
into the game by spawning multiple enemies
all over the screen over time.
In our SpawnManager class,
we have exactly everything
that we need to be able to spawn
multiple enemies over time.
And in order to do that, we're
going to use something called
a 'for-loop'.
Now, a for-loop is similar
to an if-statement,
where with an if-statement,
we used a condition
to be able to see if something was true.
For example, with something in our game,
if the player picks up a power-up.
A for-loop will enable us
to control the iterations
that something goes through.
So if we want something
to execute five times,
we can do that.
For example,
if we want to have our Instantiate
method happen five times,
we can use a for-loop.
So, in our Start method, if
we type in the keyword "for",
the way a for-loop works is
that we actually need
three different parameters
to be able to use this loop.
First, we need to tell the
for-loop where to start.
So we're going to create
a variable in here
for our start point, and
we'll just call it "i",
and we'll set it to zero.
Now we need to tell the
for-loop the condition
of when it should stop.
As long as 'i' is less than
three, then it should continue.
Once 'i' is not less than three,
this will make our for-loop stop running,
since the condition won't be true anymore.
And then we need to tell the for-loop
how we're going get
'i' from zero to three.
So we can say "i=i+1".
Another way that we can do this is similar
to how we multiply values by itself.
We can just say "i+=1".
But if we actually want an even
shorter way of saying 'i+=1'
we can actually just say "i++"
and C# will know that this
should just add one to 'i'
every time the for-loop goes through.
So what'll happen is
'i' will be set to zero,
it'll make an enemy, and
it'll add one to 'i',
so that 'i' is equal to one.
Then it'll make another enemy,
same thing, 'i' becomes two.
And then it'll make another
enemy, adds one to 'i'.
And then it'll stop making enemies.
And then we just need to
wrap this entire thing
in its own block, using our curly braces.
So now this'll create three enemies.
Now when we press play,
you should see that we
have three enemies spawn,
because they were all
created using our for-loop.
Now just to help us a little bit,
and clean up our code,
we're going to create a new
method down at the bottom.
So we'll call this "void SpawnEnemyWave()"
so that this way we can spawn our enemies.
And then we can take our code here,
put it in SpawnEnemyWave(),
and then just call SpawnEnemyWave().
So, what you're going to do,
is you're going to create a new method
called "void SpawnEnemyWave()".
In your method, you're
going to use a for-loop.
You're going to use the variable 'i',
set it to zero.
When 'i' is less than three,
then this for-loop will stop.
Increment 'i' plus one every time,
and then just call the Instantiate method
for our enemy prefab.
And then call SpawnEnemyWave
in your start method.
Now it's your turn.
(synthetic chime)