(tech-sounding chimes)
- [Instructor] We've
got a for-loop set up,
so now when we press play,
you can see the three different
enemies spawning around.
If we're going to increase the number
of enemies that spawn in our game,
we'll actually need to be
able to pass information
to our method using parameters.
In our spawn manager script,
we have our SpawnEnemyWave method.
Now, how do we actually add parameters
to our method, so that way
we can tell it numbers of enemies
that we want to spawn over time?
In fact, it's fairly easy.
What we can do is, we can type in
int enemiesToSpawn,
and now this creates an
enemiesToSpawn variable
that we can then use throughout our code.
So, instead of ending
or for-loop when i < 3,
we can end our for-loop
when i < enemiesToSpawn .
We've been using
parameters the entire time
with a lot of our methods,
to be able to pass in information
like enemyPrefab, or transform.rotation,
and in this case, we can use something
as simple as a integer variable
to pass in the number of enemies
that we want to spawn,
every time we call this method.
One thing you'll notice
is our SpawnEnemyWave method
at our Start method
is pretty angry with us right now,
because it actually needs
a number to start with.
So, we can press 3,
and now when we play our game,
we should just see three
enemies spawn once again.
So, you can see that adding parameters
to our methods can be
a fairly easy process.
Then, if we wanted to, we could just use
something as simple as a comma,
and state another random thing
to be able to use a second variable.
And, we can add in as many
parameters as we want,
but it's best to keep the parameters
to as minimum as possible
so that way you're not using
too many things, if you don't need to.
One other point to mention here,
you can see that here
in our SpawnEnemyWave,
we have a "void" method,
and then in our GenerateSpawnPosition,
we have a "Vector3".
So, you can see here
the difference in when
you would really use
a "void" method, versus a
method that returns something.
Where with our GenerateSpawnPosition,
we want it to give us information
on a random position
that we want to generate,
versus our SpawnEnemyWave
method is just doing something.
In this case, doing the task
of creating different numbers of enemies,
based on how many enemies we want.
In this case too,
we need a parameter to tell SpawnEnemyWave
how many enemies we want to spawn,
but, in our GenerateSpawnPosition,
we don't need any parameters
because it's already doing
all the calculations inside of the method.
So, what you're gonna do is,
in your SpawnEnemyWave method,
you're going to add a parameter,
which is a int of the
number of enemiesToSpawn.
You're going to replace the 3
in i < 3 of your for-loop,
with the enemiesToSpawn variable,
and then in your "Start" method,
just make sure that in SpawnEnemyWave,
you add an integer in there
to tell the method how many enemies
you want to spawn.
Now it's your turn.
(tech-sounding chimes)