(computerized chirping)
- [Narrator] So, we're
using loops to control
all of the spawning of our enemies
but one of the things that we have to do,
is we actually need to make it
so when all of these enemies fall off,
you can see they still exist in our scene.
So actually, I need to remove them
and then we'll add in some functionality
to spawn new waves.
First what we're gonna do
is in our enemy script,
we're going to remove the enemies
when they fall off the scene.
So we'll do that in our Update method
so we can always check their position.
So, if the enemy's current position
on the y becomes less than negative 10,
so if it falls below
plane of our platform,
then we'll destroy the
current game object, cool?
So now, in our SpawnManager,
since we know that our
enemies will be destroyed
when they leave the platform,
we actually want to
keep track of the number
of enemies that we have.
So, we're going to make
a public variable for now
so we can see the numbers of enemies
that are the screen.
We'll make it an int
and then we'll just call it enemyCount
so we can keep track.
In our Update method,
is actually where we're
going to be keeping the count
of all of our enemies.
They will be deleted at
different points in time,
so we use enemyCount and we'll
set this using a new method
to find all of the enemies in the scene.
So, if we use FindObjectsOfType.
So, in this case, this
method will be looking for
all of the different objects in our scene,
but now we can actually use our script
to be able to find all of those objects.
So we'll actually use the Enemy script,
since all of our enemies will be spawning
with that script on it.
So, similar to how you use GetComponent
and that type of component.
With FindObjectsOfType,
you can use the name
of the scripts applied
to those game objects
to find those objects.
And now, you can see
we have a problem here.
So, this is actually a really useful part
of knowing the difference
between return and void now.
So actually, if we hover
over FindObjectsOfType,
you can see that first
word says it returns
an array of enemies and the problem here
is that it can't actually
set an array of enemies
to an integer.
You need an integer to set an integer.
So actually, because this is an array,
we can actually use the Length method.
And so now length will
actually return the number
of enemy objects in our scene.
So now that we can keep track
of all the different enemies,
we'll need to know when we
should spawn more enemies.
So, we'll use an if statement
to track that condition, so
if the enemyCount ever becomes
or, using our comparison operator here
with the two equal signs, zero,
then we should spawn more enemies.
And just to see and make sure it works,
I'll set this to one for now.
So after all three of our
enemies fall off the scene,
our Enemy Count should hit zero
and then it will spawn one more enemy.
So now in Unity, if I
select our Spawn Manager
in our project hierarchy you can see
that the current Enemy Count is zero.
When I play our game,
you can see three enemies
spawn, I pick up the power-up,
one enemy falls off, two
enemies, three enemies fall off,
get set to zero, and then
it sets it back to one
because it spawns a new enemy.
So, what you're gonna do
is in your enemy script,
you're going to add some lines of code
just to detect when an
enemy falls off the scene
to be destroyed, in our Update method.
In our SpawnManager script,
you're going to create a new variable.
We'll make it public for
now so we can see it change.
We'll make it an integer
called enemyCount.
In our Update method, we're
going to set enemyCount
by finding ObjectsOfType,
and the type we're gonna use
is actually the enemy script.
And then we need to get the Length
of what that returns
because it actually gives us
an array and we just need a number.
Then we're gonna create
a new if statement,
using the enemyCount.
And when enemyCount becomes zero,
then we'll spawn a new
enemy wave with one enemy.
So, now it's your turn.